JOJO SEXTON

PROFILE

I am a professional banker who builds applications in my free time. I have been lending for a decade and I thoroughly enjoy the job

I am now looking for a role in a company that will allow me to utilise my skills and as I am passionate about developing banking applications, testing and cyber security.

SKILLS

BANKING:

- 10 years experience in banking and finance
- Debt and credit management
- Extensive knowledge of banking and accounting practices and procedures.
- Understanding of compliance and tax planning
- Experience in corporate and small business accounting
- Corporate and SME financial analysing
- Strong customer service

IT & PROGRAMMING:

- Advanced with Microsoft 356 (Word, Excel and PowerPoint, Teams, Outlook)
- Front End Styles: Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator;
 Procreate
- Front End Basics: HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Front End Frameworks: React, Redux, API Client
- Back End: Node.js, Express, API
- Database: SQLite3
- Testing: Jest, Cheerio, Supertest
- Others: Git and Git hub, Agile software development methodologies

EDUCATION

ENSPIRAL DEV ACADEMY AOTEAROA - NZQA LEVEL 6 - FULL STACK DEVELOPER - 2022 STRATEGI - NZQA LEVEL 5 - NEW ZEALAND CERTIFICATE IN FINANCIAL SERVICES - 2023 VICTORIA, UNIVERSITY OF WELLINGTON - BACHELOR DEGREE - MAJORING IN FINANCE AND COMMERCIAL LAW - 2008

EXPERIENCE

LENDING ADVISER/ BROKER MANAGER 2022, TSB BANK-CURRENT

Assessing lending applications from mortgage advisers.

Building strong relationships with the advisers and maintaining effective communication can help to ensure successful outcomes for both parties. This includes understanding borrower needs, maintaining regular contact, and being responsive to any issues that may arise.-Assessing lending applications from mortgage advisers. -Building strong relationships with the advisers and maintaining effective communication can help to ensure successful outcomes for both parties. This includes understanding borrower needs, maintaining regular contact, and being responsive to any issues that may arise.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER/ STUDENT, ENSPIRAL DEV ACADEMY, 2021

I was in the banking industry for more than 8 years. I have a strong passion for lending and love helping people get into their first home or looking at purchasing their first property. I also have ideas around developing lending apps and platforms for the banking industry, which can make it easier for lenders to assess credit applications, while meeting compliance and credit policy requirements.

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER/ STUDENT, ENSPIRAL DEV ACADEMY, 2021 (CONTINUED)

In August 2021, I resigned my corporate job and joined a coding boot-camp at Dev Academy. Coding was always something I wanted to learn but there was never enough time, motivation or resources. So when the opportunity presented itself, I took it with both hands.

With no background in IT previously, I went from no stack to full stack developer in 15 weeks. It's been a great journey going thru the training at EDA. It has not only provided me the fundamental of coding but also how to be a good programmer, build quality codes that last and testing along the way. More than that, I've been taught human skills that I need the most to thrive in the future digital workplace. After the training, I am more confident with working in a team, know how to handle difficult conversations and resolve conflict.



https://github.com/jojo-sexton

CUSTOMER BANKING CONSULTANT, WESTPAC NZ - 2016-2021

- I have been in the banking industry for more than 8 years and have been home lending for 3 of those years. I have a strong passion for home lending. I love helping people get into their first home or looking at purchasing their first investment property.
- I am skilled in Banking, Technical Support, Credit Analysis & Consumer Lending.
- My current job is handling a large portfolio of mortgage brokers and liaising with solicitors for settlement. I am a senior consultant who can handle complex customer enquiries that ranges from Home Lending, Construction Lending, Business lending to Personal Lending - Investment products and Insurance products.
- I have substantial understanding of bank policies and procedures as well as the compliance, RBNZ legislations and the housing market which I update continuously

OFFICE ADMINISTRATION, NEW WORLD SUPERMARKET - AUG 2012 - FEB 2016

Supporting the business by producing and maintaining accurate financial and management accounting information on which financial decisions are based.

Accounts Payable and Receivables

ASSISTANT RELATIONSHIP MANAGER, MULTINATIONAL CORPORATIONS, HSBC - 2009-2012

- Assisted relationship managers to manage and develop the portfolios comprising top and mid-tier multinational corporations in the field of consumer retail.
- Regularly assessed capital requirements of existing clients and prospects and provided them with the best loan solutions available.
- Prepare credit applications, credit renewals and undertake periodic reviews of credit files and facilities.
- Liaise with the legal department, risk management, and external consultants to review loan documentation and ensure open communication throughout all stages of loan deals.

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.